Andrew O'Connell

721 W Buckingham Pl. Chicago, IL 60657 | (630) 917-9099 aoconnell099@gmail.com | https://github.com/aoconnell099

Expected: Dec. 2020

SUMMARY

Bachelor of Science candidate in Computer Science. Have worked in a team to conduct extended research and present findings at an academic symposium. Passionate about learning new technologies and constantly looks for implementation methods to increase efficiency.

EDUCATION

University of Illinois at Chicago (UIC)

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 3.00/4.00

SKILLS

Languages: C++, Java, Javascript, CSS, HTML, Python Frameworks: React, React Native, Selenium, Phaser Software: Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook Databases: Firebase, IndexedDB, Microsoft Access

PROJECTS

- Job searching mobile app published on Expo
- Fully functioning retro arcade gaming machine and media player using a Raspberry Pi 3
- Two dimensional web arcade game
- CTA train tracker clone app
- Chicago food inspection results app
- Text based pseudo Artificial Intelligence guessing game
- Text based recursive boggle board solver

LEADERSHIP

Member of the Chicago Engineering Design Team at UIC.

Spring 2017 - Fall 2018

- Attended meetings
- Assisted in battlebot structural and software conceptual design
- Volunteered as a counselor at the Muscular Dystrophy Association's Summer Camp; promoted to cabin leader in 2014 and 2015.

Summer 2010 - 2015

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jefferson Tap & Grille - Chicago, IL

Barback

July 2018 - September 2019

Maintain the area surrounding the bar. Stock the bar on an ongoing basis while serving food and drinks, receiving orders, and cleaning tables. Work in a group to ensure a seamless service for large parties for up to 150 people.

John O'Connell Plumbing - Glen Ellyn, IL

Assistant Plumber

June 2009 - Aug. 2013;

May 2015 - May 2018

Measured, cleaned, cut, and joined copper, PVC, and gas piping to fit the specified requirements for the job. Interacted with the customer and explained any technicalities they were confused about.

Received calls and scheduled new jobs based on our current calendar.

Wheaton Nurseries - Wheaton, IL

Landscaper; Nursery Caretaker

May 2014 - Aug 2014

Worked on a crew of 2-5 people to perform full scale commercial and residential land renovations. Maintained proper hydration needs and stem care for hundreds of plants, shrubs, and trees. Helped customers find plants and discussed other possibilities based on their preference to prove the

Helped customers find plants and discussed other possibilities based on their preference to prove the best possible customer service.